the goal of blackjack is to have a hand
that totals higher than the dealer's but
doesn't total to higher than 21 if your
hand totals higher than 21 it is called
a bust which means you are out of the
game the game starts with everyone
besides the dealer placing a bet then
the dealer deals one card face up to
each player and one card face up to
themselves
everyone is dealt one more face-up card
besides the dealer whose second card is
dealt face down cards 2 through 10 are
scored using their face value and Jack's
queens and kings are all equal to 10
aces can be either 1 or 11 and you can
choose their value throughout the round
if you have one if your two face-up
cards total 21 you automatically win one
and a half times your bet from the
dealer and you're done for that round
otherwise the dealer asked whether you
want another card from the top of the
deck if you do say hit or motion toward
yourself with your hand there's no limit
to how many cards you can ask for but
once your hand totals higher than 21 you
bust and the dealer gets your bet if you
don't want any more cards say stay or
wave your hand over the table once the
dealer has gone around the table they
flip up their facedown card if it is 16
or under they have to take another card
if it's 17 or higher they have to stay
with their hand if the deal
bust every player that's still in that
round wins twice their bet however if
the dealer doesn't bust only the player
whose hands are higher than the dealer's
win twice their bet everyone else loses
their initial bet once the round is over
all of the players place a new bet and
another round begins